# Kelly Ann Marshall

# Web Development + Web Design + Print Design + Photography

BFA Photography, MSc Information Technology (Merit)

+44 (0)7906 117 249 kelly\_ann\_marshall@yahoo.com

https://kellyannmarshall.github.io

# Summary

Talented frontend developer and designer with over 29 years of professional experience who is self-motivated, client-centric, creative, insightful and versatile. Adept at innovating user experience for web applications. Exceptional interpersonal skills and is efficient, organised, resourceful, flexible, reliable and willing to listen and contribute with clients and team members. Available for contract and permanent positions based in Glasgow City Centre or 100% remote.

#### Skills

- HTML(5)
- CSS(3) / SASS / LESS
- JavaScript / ES6 / jQuery
- · Angular / Vue.js
- · Node / Webpack
- Docker / AWS / Jenkins
- · Git / Bitbucket / SVN
- Jasmine / Karma / Jest / Cypress
- Mapbox / OpenLayers

- Jekyll / Joomla / Wordpress / Eleventy
- Responsive Web Design
- Wireframing / Prototyping
- Progressive Enhancement
- W3C Standards & Accessibility
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Balsamiq / Figma / Adobe XD
- Cross-Browser Compatibility
- Google Analytics

# **Professional Experience**

Senior Developer (Aug 2020 - Jun 2022)

Idox Group (acquired thinkWhere in Oct 2021), Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: Angular, Typescript, RxJS, OpenLayers, Python, Flask, Bootstrap, Cypress, AWS, pgAdmin, Docker, Terraform, IIS, Figma, AdobeXD, Balsamiq, Git, Jira

- Worked as part of an agile development team with a focus on design and UI development of groundMapper, a fully-featured cloud service GIS data application
- Wireframing, UI design and front-end development of advanced search functionality, split-screen map / data views and bespoke forestry data management features
- Development and delivery of new admin features for groundMapper including permissions and account, project and user management
- UI design and front-end development of Eurogeographics Open Maps for Europe website, a resource for official European map, geospatial and land information

UI Developer (Aug 2018 - Feb 2020)

VisitScotland, Edinburgh, Scotland

Technologies: Vue.js, MapboxGL, Node, Webpack, Gulp, Cypress, Bloomreach Experience CMS, Java, Freemarker, Bitbucket, Jira

- Worked as part of an internal development team tasked with major re-platforming project for VisitScotland's flagship website, www.visitscotland.com
- Created proof of concept interactive tourism destination maps with focus on accessibility, including rich features such as filtering and sorting destination product and event data

#### Front-End Developer (Aug 2017 - May 2018)

Peninsula Business Services, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, LESS, AngularJS, JavaScript / ES6, Node, Gulp, Git, Karma, Jasmine, VSCode, Jenkins, WebAPIs, Microsoft Team Foundation Server

- HTML, CSS/LESS and JavaScript development for an internal task management system built as a single page web application using AngularJS.
- Liaised with development team to research and implement Postcode Anywhere API service in a client address search and entry feature.
- Refactored project CSS/LESS directory structure and added automated css code linting to the project, making the project files easier to maintain.

## Front-End Developer (Feb 2014 - May 2017)

Arnold Clark, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node, Grunt, Gulp, Git, Backbone, Jekyll, Joomla, Jasmine

- As part of an agile web development team, I worked on the client-side HTML, CSS/SASS and JavaScript development for Arnold Clark's rental and leasing websites, which included:
  - https://www.arnoldclarkrental.com
  - https://www.autocentre.acvm.com
  - https://www.acvm.com
- Liaised with Worldpay technical support team and back-end developer to upgrade legacy online payment system on https://www.arnoldclarkrental.com to Worldpay's Hosted Payment Pages. The new system was responsive on tablet and mobile devices by default and contributed to a 21% increase in mobile revenue vs the month prior to the switch
- Worked with team Web Designer and Product Owner to simplify and add a Guest Checkout feature to the checkout process on https://www.arnoldclarkrental.com. This combined with other website improvements contributed to a 31% increase in revenue overall for 2016 vs 2015
- Converted legacy CSS files to SASS and added Grunt.js tasks compile and minify assets for https://www.arnoldclarkrental.com, making the website project files more organised and easier to maintain
- Developed news feature at https://www.acvm.com/news/ which includes continuous loading articles, article search function and category filters

# **Previous Experience**

#### Web Content Officer (Oct 2012 - Nov 2013)

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: T4 content management system, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, WAMP, HeidiSQL, jQuery, Javascript, AJAX, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

# Web Developer / Research Assistant (Oct 2011 - Sep 2012)

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: Django web application framework, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Excel, LaTex, OmniGraffle.

#### Print and Web Designer (Feb 2008 - Sept 2010)

Admit One, New York, NY

Technologies: Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Fireworks, Flash, Acrobat, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Microsoft Visual Studio, HTML, CSS, IQuery, JavaScript.

#### Print and Web Designer (Nov 2002 - Nov 2007)

Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, Rockville, MD

Technologies: Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, GoLive, Fireworks, Flash, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### Print and Web Designer (Feb 1999 - Dec 2000)

LADO International College, Washington, DC

#### Advertising Designer (Jun 1996 - Jan 1999)

Channing Bete, South Deerfield, MA

## Freelance Designer (May 1994 - May 1996)

New York, NY

## Digital Retoucher (Jun 1993 - May 1994)

Digital Stock Connection, Rockville, MD

#### Education

# Master of Science in Information Technology (Sep 2010 - Sep 2011)

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, Scotland

Emphasis: Programming in Java, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, XML, HTML, CSS, Django, Python, Multimedia Systems, Software Project Management, Information Systems and Databases

Dissertation: A web Interface for the purchase of live event tickets with interactive venue maps built with SVG, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL

Activities: Postgraduate Student Representative

#### Bachelor of Fine Arts in Photography (Sep 1989 - Jun 1993)

Maryland Institute, College of Art, Baltimore, Maryland

Emphasis: B&W and colour photography and development, film and video production, photochemistry, alternative photo processes, studio lighting, 2D design, computer illustration, painting, drawing, sculpture, art history and the history of photography

# International Student Mobility (Sep 1991 - Dec 1991)

Edinburgh Napier University, Edinburgh, Scotland

Emphasis: Commercial B&W and colour photography and development, studio lighting, photojournalism, medium and large format photography